<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>krestomatio on My Dev Blog</title><link>https://jobcespedes.dev/tags/krestomatio/</link><description>Recent content in krestomatio on My Dev Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>© 2020 Job Céspedes Ortiz</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 09:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jobcespedes.dev/tags/krestomatio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Running Virtual Machines on Orange Pi 5</title><link>https://jobcespedes.dev/2023/11/running-virtual-machines-on-orange-pi-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jobcespedes.dev/2023/11/running-virtual-machines-on-orange-pi-5/</guid><description>In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll walk through the steps to install libvirt on the Single Board Computer (SBC) Orange Pi 5 (opi5) for running virtual machines (VMs). I&amp;rsquo;ve compiled these steps after dealing with the opi5 instructions, searching on the internet and communities, and my own experience. I hope this guide helps someone accomplish this task more quickly than I did initially.
Installing Orange Pi 5 The first step is to install an Operating System (OS) on the opi5.</description></item><item><title>A KeyDB Operator</title><link>https://jobcespedes.dev/2022/01/a-keydb-operator/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 23:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jobcespedes.dev/2022/01/a-keydb-operator/</guid><description>KeyDB is a multithreading, drop-in alternative to Redis. The Keydb-operator can easily create either a standalone instance (1 replica) or a multimaster setup (3 replicas) of the KeyDB in-memory database. When KeyDB is in multimaster mode, it is possible to have more than one master, allowing for read/write operations across all of them. This capability enhances high availability and fault tolerance.
This operator is part of the Kubernetes operators and tools developed by Krestomatio, a managed service for Moodle™ instances</description></item><item><title>A Kubernetes NFS Operator</title><link>https://jobcespedes.dev/2021/07/a-kubernetes-nfs-operator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 13:55:42 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jobcespedes.dev/2021/07/a-kubernetes-nfs-operator/</guid><description>NFS Operator creates NFSv4 ganesha servers in Kubernetes, allowing to set ownership/permissions of their NFS export directory; to autoexpand their PVC; and to enable RWX storage from them:
It can set ownership and permissions for export parent directory of the (NFS) Ganesha server. It is able to expand/adjust the PVC size of the (NFS) Ganesha server automatically, as it grows. It could autogenerate an StorageClass that uses the (NFS) Ganesha server for RWX storage.</description></item><item><title>A Minimal Container Image for Rocky Linux 8</title><link>https://jobcespedes.dev/2021/06/a-minimal-container-image-for-rocky-linux-8/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 18:55:42 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jobcespedes.dev/2021/06/a-minimal-container-image-for-rocky-linux-8/</guid><description>Now that Rocky Linux is GA, here is a repo for a minimal container image for Rocky Linux. Its size is around ~37 MB (compressed). It is based on Fedora Minimal and UBI8 minimal from Red Hat. You can download it from Quay or build it, following the instructions in the repo. You could also generate a new rootfs yourself before building the image, again, following the short instructions in the repo.</description></item></channel></rss>