<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>orangepi5 on My Dev Blog</title><link>https://jobcespedes.dev/tags/orangepi5/</link><description>Recent content in orangepi5 on My Dev Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>© 2023 Job Céspedes Ortiz</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 12:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jobcespedes.dev/tags/orangepi5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a K3s Cluster with Armbian on Orange Pi 5 Plus</title><link>https://jobcespedes.dev/2023/11/building-a-k3s-cluster-with-armbian-on-orange-pi-5-plus/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jobcespedes.dev/2023/11/building-a-k3s-cluster-with-armbian-on-orange-pi-5-plus/</guid><description>In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll be my sharing hands-on experience in building a K3s Cluster on the Orange Pi 5 Plus (opi5+) using Armbian as the Operating System (OS) and Ansible. The post is meant as a straightforward guide for anyone looking to replicate the process. I hope it proves helpful for your own setup.
Please consider that in some sections, there are references to external guides containing the respective steps.</description></item><item><title>Building a K3s Cluster with Fedora CoreOS on Orange Pi 5 Plus</title><link>https://jobcespedes.dev/2023/11/building-a-k3s-cluster-with-fedora-coreos-on-orange-pi-5-plus/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 11:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jobcespedes.dev/2023/11/building-a-k3s-cluster-with-fedora-coreos-on-orange-pi-5-plus/</guid><description>This blog post summarizes my unsuccessful attempt to build a K3s Cluster on the Orange Pi 5 Plus (opi5+) using Fedora CoreOS (FCOS). It also outlines the steps taken before arriving at that conclusion and presents a list of possible alternatives to achieve a similar result.
Why Fedora CoreOS? The main reasons behind selecting FCOS as the Operating System (OS) were:
Automatic Updates: Fedora CoreOS follows an automated update model, and reboots can also be orchestrated using Zincati.</description></item><item><title>Running Virtual Machines on Orange Pi 5</title><link>https://jobcespedes.dev/2023/11/running-virtual-machines-on-orange-pi-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jobcespedes.dev/2023/11/running-virtual-machines-on-orange-pi-5/</guid><description>In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll walk through the steps to install libvirt on the Single Board Computer (SBC) Orange Pi 5 (opi5) for running virtual machines (VMs). I&amp;rsquo;ve compiled these steps after dealing with the opi5 instructions, searching on the internet and communities, and my own experience. I hope this guide helps someone accomplish this task more quickly than I did initially.
Installing Orange Pi 5 The first step is to install an Operating System (OS) on the opi5.</description></item></channel></rss>