<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>IaC on My Dev Blog</title><link>https://jobcespedes.dev/tags/iac/</link><description>Recent content in IaC on My Dev Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>© 2020 Job Céspedes Ortiz</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 18:14:42 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jobcespedes.dev/tags/iac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simple Testing of Complex Scenarios</title><link>https://jobcespedes.dev/2020/05/simple-testing-of-complex-scenarios/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 18:14:42 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jobcespedes.dev/2020/05/simple-testing-of-complex-scenarios/</guid><description>Is there something easy when deploying and configuring the database layer?
Aspects of Data integrity and reliable/safe operations add up to complexity, which only increases when tradicional SQL, high availability, fault tolerance, scalability and high levels of concurrency, are required. It is a sensitive layer, no doubt. Consequently, if there is something easy there, it would be to screw everything up.
Do not fear, go test, screw up and learn. I mean, just not in production.</description></item><item><title>Multiple Environments in Ansible</title><link>https://jobcespedes.dev/2020/02/multiple-environments-in-ansible/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 14:14:42 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://jobcespedes.dev/2020/02/multiple-environments-in-ansible/</guid><description>Many systems are deployed in a multienvironment context, for example: production, stage, and dev. These environments often share variables and artifacts. In Ansible, there are different methods to work in this context. For example, separate directory layout and soft links. However, it can end with a considerable amount of data and duplicate files between environments, exposing variables to all hosts or adding much more complexity to playbooks.
Demo multienv tests a stackable multienvironment directory layout for Ansible, using multienv Ansible role.</description></item></channel></rss>